# Jonathan Aizlewood

# Senior Visual Designer at Clearleft Ltd

jaizlewood@carbongraffiti.com

# Summary

Coming from a past life as a digital marketer, I've since pivoted into digital design... and I haven't looked back. However I'm still able to draw upon a large body of marketing knowledge that helps me design meaningful but effective digital experiences across all digital channels. I specialise in visual design: good UX thinking manifested in a function and a desirable, enjoyable form that helps users attain their goals. Specialties: Digital design, responsive design, email design, UX, front-end development

# Experience

# Senior Visual Designer at Clearleft Ltd

August 2012 - Present (3 years 5 months)

Clearleft is an award-winning User Experience agency based in Brighton. At Clearleft I work as a Visual Designer, which is the combination of aesthetic appeal and emotional design in order to express the underlying user experience. http://clearleft.com/is/jon-aizlewood

# Member of Advisory Board at The Pie (Professionals in International Education)

August 2011 - Present (4 years 5 months)

## Managing Director at CarbonGraffiti Ltd

September 2009 - Present (6 years 4 months)

CarbonGraffiti offers freelance digital marketing and design services direct to SMBs, and partners with digital agencies to provide marketing support, production, consultation and campaign management. Offered services include the following, all backed by more than 7 years of corporate digital marketing experience and a passion for great design: -- Email marketing and pay-per-click campaign design, implementation and management -- Website design & coding (Wordpress, Shopify, Magento) -- Existing channels including Social media and emerging channels such as Mobile design, QR codes, mobile applications -- Digital marketing strategy & consulting

#### Member of website committee - lead designer & developer at Brighton digital festival

July 2011 - September 2011 (3 months)

Designed and developed the Brighton Digital Festival's 2011 (and inaugural) website for the September festival.

#### E-Marketing Manager, Digital Sales Department, UK at Study Group

October 2007 - September 2009 (2 years)

E-Marketing Manager for a large International education provider with operating divisions in the UK, US and Australia as well as Regional offices in 120 countries throughout the world. Responsibilities included the planning and management of multilingual e-marketing campaigns targeting potential students across 120 countries via channels including (but not limited to) pay-per-click (incl. Yandex, Baidu, Yahoo, MSN and Google), email marketing, social media, strategy and planning, analysis and line management.

#### Freelance Web Designer at CarbonGraffiti

2005 - September 2009 (4 years)

CarbonGraffiti is a web identity used to represent my knowledge of, and continual interest in, all things online marketing-related. It is effectively my sandbox, used to self-promote, discuss online marketing-related topics, and acquire new business opportunities.

#### Manager, Online Marketing at GOT Corporation

November 2005 - March 2007 (1 year 5 months)

Pay Per Click advertising with Google, Yahoo, and MSN programs, SEO (search engine optimization), email marketing design, programming and execution adhering to best practices, overall web design, email newsletter design, online marketing lead generation programs, adnetworks, banner advertising (design, CPM), ample experience with photoshop, HTML, some Flash and Print design.

# **Marketing Specialist at GOT Corporation**

January 2005 - December 2005 (1 year)

#### AR Manager at Hatley

2002 - 2003 (1 year)

# Skills & Expertise

web strategy

Website Redesign

**HTML** 

**Email Marketing** 

**Digital Marketing** 

**PPC** 

Web Design

**Web Analytics** 

**Online Marketing** 

**Marketing Strategy** 

Wordpress

**CMS** 

**CSS** 

**Web Development** 

**User Experience** 

**Digital Strategy** 

**B2B** 

**SEM** 

**Strategic Planning** 

Html5

Responsive design

**Mobile first** 

CSS3

**jQuery** 

**Email Design** 

**Online Branding** 

**User-centered Design** 

**Mobile Design** 

**Web Consultancy** 

**Blogging** 

WordPress

**Interaction Design** 

**Online Advertising** 

# Education

# **Concordia University**

1997 - 2001

## Honors and Awards

Received BA Hons, Human Environment, Concordia University Runner up, DIMAS (Digital Media Awards:South), 2007, for 'Freelancer of the Year'

#### **Interests**

CSS website design, web design and graphics, email marketing template/mailer design, pay-per-click techniques, word-of-mouth marketing

# Jonathan Aizlewood

Senior Visual Designer at Clearleft Ltd

jaizlewood@carbongraffiti.com



# 24 people have recommended Jonathan

"I have had the pleasure of working on a visual language with Jon for the last year. He has demonstrated great sensitivity to organizational needs, as well as creativity in solving our problems. He has a good eye for the important details, without losing track of project objectives. It is my belief that Jon will be a committed and creative contribution to any project, and I have no problem recommend him to others."

# — **Henning Kruhaug**, *Specialist - User Interface and Research*, *Nordea*, worked directly with Jonathan at Clearleft Ltd

"Superlatives are required to explain working with Jon - extremely understanding, patient, friendly and easy to deal with; with an intuitive grasp of what we required or needed. Ahead of the game in terms of responsive design. He helped us launch an online news-and-jobs platform that has exceeded our expectations in terms of creating a strong brand allegiance. Our design has been complimented by many in our sector and played a huge part in helping our start-up get up and go."

#### — Amy Baker, was Jonathan's client

"I worked with Jonathan Aizlewood from Carbon Graffiti on our latest delegate management/guest list campaign at Virgin Galactic for our milestone event of 2012. Jon was very easy to work with. He understood our brand and requirements extremely well and quickly produced an efficient solution to suit our business needs without breaking the bank. Having previously used various methods and delegate management tools, Jon provided us with the clear and informative expertise that we were looking for on a one-to-one level and the reassurance of a dedicated consultant to help assist our campaign at the professional level we were looking for. I would certainly look at working with Carbon Graffiti again and would happily encourage others to do so too! Michelle Jackley Marketing Production & Logistics Executive, Virgin Galactic"

#### — Michelle Jackley, was Jonathan's client

"I've worked with Jon over the last couple of years on a number of websites both for Fabrica and related projects but also as a member of the steering group for the Brighton Digital Festival on the development of that website. Jon is without fail a pleasure to work with. He is energetic, knowledgeable, creative and thoughtful of our needs. We are about to start work on another project together and I have no hesitation in recommending him."

## — Laurence Hill, was Jonathan's client

"I am very happy to have worked with Jonathan and highly recommend him. I love the website he created as well as the newsletter. He was always there to answer questions and walk me through the entire process."

# — Carolyn Stotesbery, was Jonathan's client

"Jonathon delivered an excellent service to USL for the design and buld of their small new B2B website. It was a rushed project and he dealt with our unreasonable client demands with aplomb and tact. Jonathon has a deep technical understanding of how contemporray websites need to work. He does not however allow this technical mastery to stop him from providing clear and patient advice to his clients. I would highly recommend him."

# — Nick Tellwright, was Jonathan's client

"Jonathan proved helpful and reliable during our experience with him in producing CSS for a website."

# — Jo Chipchase, was Jonathan's client

"Jon was initially contracted to re-design our website earlier this year. From the outset he was great to work with and it was apparent that he was hugely creative, but not only that, he understood what it was we were trying to achieve due to his professional experience prior to branching out on his own. Jon was hugely flexible throughout the process and very professional, meeting deadlines we had set and delivering what was expected and more. Since the website went live, we have also worked with Jon on various other pieces that we have needed to help develop the Onalytica brand (he designed our corporate presentation templates slides as well as other key collateral for use at events etc.) and all has been impressive and well received. I would not hesitate to recommend Jon, and hope that I can work with him again as and when we are in need of his expertise!"

# — Becky Hayward, was Jonathan's client

"Jonathan has helped us to improve our BMJ email campaigns in terms of look and feel, viral functionality and usability. Working with both our internal teams and external email vendors, Jonathan has been both professional and proactive at helping us to implement changes to existing campaigns, as well as to suggest creative ways to present our range of information on our new US targeted campaigns. It has been a pleasure to work with Jonathan, and I would definitely recommend him to friends and colleagues seeking guidance and expert assistance with digital marketing."

#### — Susan Harrington, was Jonathan's client

"Jon was briefed to help develop a brand identity and logo for my company, WAVA. We worked together very closely on the concept, the competitive environment, the values that underpin the company's mission,

and the commercial and long-term objectives. He grasped the implications straight away, and produced viable design concepts within the time and budget constraints throughout the process. Over a short period of time, Jon developed these initial concepts into truly inspired ideas, that stretched the emotional power of the brand to areas I had previously not considered. After further iterations, as well as a consultation among our customers and stakeholders, Jon produced final work of a very high standard - mature, thoughtful, original, powerful, contemporary and very versatile. Since we launched the brand, we have had nothing but positive feedback and our recognition in the market is increasing every day. The brand has serious long-term life in it. Jon is not just highly skilled and intuitive - he's a great person to work with. Fast, responsive, accurate and never stressed about deadlines. He gives the client confidence and reassurance. I look forward to working with Jon on direct marketing projects - I am certain he will deliver work of the same high calibre."

#### — Ricard Giner i Sariola, was Jonathan's client

"Jon is a great addition to the team. He is smart, fun and knows his stuff. He single-handedly manages all emarketing for multiple brands across multiple countries. He's very good at writing really nifty reports with charts and nice diagrams and everything. He also brightens up the office with his occasional pink t-shirts which is always a bonus. He'll go far (but hopefully not too soon)."

# — Louise Courtney, worked directly with Jonathan at Study Group

"Working with Jonathan is a pleasure. He knows his field better than anyone I've met and his passion for elegant solutions that get the job done is inspiring. If I have a question about his field I know he'll have already considered it deeply himself and it's great to work with someone who can do all of this with a bright smile and sense of fun. A good friend to have on your team."

#### — Michael Rose, worked directly with Jonathan at Study Group

"Jon came to Study Group as a breath of fresh air, with his extensive knowledge of, and enthusiasm for, all aspects of online marketing. Always up to date with the latest trends and protocols, he can be relied on for diligent, quick, effective work."

## — Myfanwy Nixon, worked directly with Jonathan at Study Group

"Jon was able to run with list of requirements to provide a recommended framework and web site structure; from there, the work was well done including the content in both French and English with little rework or follow ups required. We were able to get our site up and running within the expected timeframe; additional updates were also done in a timely basis. Very satisfied."

#### — Michel A. Salmon, was Jonathan's client

"Jonathan is a buzzing guy full of ideas and initIatives. He's also very focused and resourceful to make those ideas happen. he's fun to work with."

#### — **franck paltrie**, worked directly with Jonathan at GOT Corporation

"Jonathan is an impressive self-starter. He goes about achieving his ambitious goals with dedication and discipline."

#### — Maxine Grossman, managed Jonathan indirectly at GOT Corporation

"Jonathon was (is) an exceptional Online Marketing Manager, who, as well as continually produing great results, was a constant source of new and innovative programs. He lives and breathes online marketing and I would whole heartedly recommend him."

#### — **Huw Griffiths**, managed Jonathan at GOT Corporation

"Jonathan spearheaded a very successful online marketing strategy for GOT Corporation when I first joined the organization and garnered a lot of praise from upper management for his hard work. He took a rather dormant aspect of our business and helped turn it into a thriving force of in-bound activity for the sales team, which obviously resulted in increased sales and revenues for the company. As a result of his keenness, dedication and thorough understanding of the online marketing space, any company would greatly benefit from having him on board."

# — **Brock Bradley**, worked with Jonathan at GOT Corporation

"Working with Jon is inspiring and motivating. He is a true team player, extremly skilled, always has innovative ideas and can deliver. He is professional and fun to work with. I would recommend Jon without hesitation."

#### — Marie Michelle Pathy, managed Jonathan indirectly at GOT Corporation

"Jon was a highly committed, creative and valued employee during his time at Got. Not only is he well versed in all the disciplines of online marketing (especially the dark "three letter" voodoos of PPC and SEO), but his dedication and disposition make him a highly recommendable employee."

#### — Jeremy Saibil, managed Jonathan indirectly at GOT Corporation

"Jonathan is a detail-oriented manager who watches the balance sheet, while focusing on the objective, and maximizes the return on every web program."

# — **Steve Smith**, managed Jonathan indirectly at GOT Corporation

"Jon is an excellent team player, who is receptive to his clients' needs in understanding their online marketing requirements enabling him to create everything, and more, required by a client. His great attitude and

dedication towards his work is reflective in all his finished products. He is absolutely a great person to work with in achieving the common goals of the company."

## — Michaelangelo Domingo, worked with Jonathan at GOT Corporation

"Jonathon is an ideal colleague; creative, efficient, reliable, and a pleasure to be around."

## — Carl Brabander, managed Jonathan at GOT Corporation

"Jonathan always present an outstanding motivation trough his work and and the level of quality he delivers is always beyond expectations. My experience of work with him as been on of my best. He is a team player and would make a great asset to any organization."

— Frederic Blache, worked directly with Jonathan at GOT Corporation

Contact Jonathan on LinkedIn